{
    "id": "abf96c41a6fa4b408786fa6674b9b792",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Sam as well as his friends ...................... studying.",
            "description": "When two nouns are connected by as well as, the verb agrees with the former subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "........................ I was annoyed, I kept quiet.",
            "description": "Either although or even though is possible here. Even though is more emphatic than although. ",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "Even if",
                "Even though"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was a child I ....................... to be an astronaut.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about past states or actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "was wanting",
                "wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The cow as well as the goat ....................... us milk.",
            "description": "When we connect two singular nouns with as well as, the verb is singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "gives",
                "is giving"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The beggar lay on the ground ......................... he were dead.",
            "description": "Either as if or as though is possible here. As if and as though are used to talk about how a situation seems.",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "though"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "....................... she was a generous woman, everyone liked her.",
            "description": "As gives the reason though is similar to but. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "Hence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is ....................... to buy a mansion.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "so rich",
                "very rich",
                "rich enough"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He was ......................... weak to even sit up.",
            "description": "Note the pattern too...to. It is also possible to write 'He was so weak that he could not even sit up.'",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "too",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The place was ......................... quiet that he decided to stay there.",
            "description": "So...that gives the cause and effect. ",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "enough",
                "such"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It was ......................... a hot day that I felt lethargic.",
            "description": "Such is used before adjective + noun.",
            "answers": [
                "such",
                "so",
                "very",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I won the lottery, I ........................ a home.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will buy",
                "would buy",
                "would have bought"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ....................... the glass, it will break.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "drop",
                "dropped",
                "had dropped"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}